[
  {
    "question": "Bradbury was a member of the",
    "a": "Springfield Writers’ Guild",
    "b": "California Writers Club",
    "c": "Tucson Science Fiction Association",
    "d": "Science Fiction Writers of America",
    "e": "Los Angeles Science Fiction Society",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which author was a mentor to Bradbury?",
    "a": "Henry Kuttner",
    "b": "Bob Olsen",
    "c": "Roger Zelazny",
    "d": "Robert Heinlein",
    "e": "John Campbell",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the title of Bradbury’s first collection of short stories?",
    "a": "Long After Midnight",
    "b": "The Martian Chronicles",
    "c": "The Illustrated Man",
    "d": "The Machineries of Joy",
    "e": "Dark Carnival",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is Bradbury’s career MOST similar to that of C.L. Moore?",
    "a": "They first published in pulp magazines.",
    "b": "They wrote several television screenplays.",
    "c": "They received the O. Henry Prize for their writing.",
    "d": "They wrote for scientific journals.",
    "e": "They wrote science fiction poetry.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bradbury originally wrote “I Sing the Body Electric” as an episode of",
    "a": "The Twilight Zone",
    "b": "Science Fiction Theatre",
    "c": "The Ray Bradbury Theater",
    "d": "Tales of Tomorrow",
    "e": "Way Out",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following awards did Bradbury NOT receive?",
    "a": "World Fantasy Award",
    "b": "National Book Foundation Medal",
    "c": "Benjamin Franklin Award",
    "d": "Grand Master Award",
    "e": "Writer’s Guild Award",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the beginning of “I Sing the Body Electric!”, the narrator proclaims that he remembers his",
    "a": "brother’s graduation",
    "b": "grandmother’s birth",
    "c": "mother’s funeral",
    "d": "father’s promotion",
    "e": "parents’ wedding",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, Who offers to be the children’s primary caretaker after their mother’s death?",
    "a": "Aunt Clara",
    "b": "Grandmother",
    "c": "Aunt Agatha",
    "d": "Uncle Timothy",
    "e": "Father",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, Father says that Fantoccini is the Italian word for",
    "a": "motherly love",
    "b": "future visions",
    "c": "caregiver",
    "d": "dream people",
    "e": "technology",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, the salesman gives Agatha a",
    "a": "key",
    "b": "puppet",
    "c": "book",
    "d": "string",
    "e": "lightbulb",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, which word does Tom translate as “The Beautiful One Is Here”?",
    "a": "Amenhotep",
    "b": "Ramesses",
    "c": "Tutankhamun",
    "d": "Cleopatra",
    "e": "Nefertiti",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does the family have to wait so long to receive the Electric Grandmother?",
    "a": "It takes a long time to assemble the complex machinery.",
    "b": "The company knows they are hesitant about their purchase.",
    "c": "The technology is very high in demand.",
    "d": "She will be shipped from halfway across the globe.",
    "e": "They need to save up enough money to purchase her first.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, the Electric Grandmother arrives in a casing adorned with",
    "a": "glass beads",
    "b": "gold hieroglyphs",
    "c": "rose petals",
    "d": "relief sculptures",
    "e": "Latin inscriptions",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the Electric Grandmother do FIRST when she was born?",
    "a": "She asks the children for their names.",
    "b": "She gives Agatha a hug.",
    "c": "She laughs.",
    "d": "She says she needs to be charged.",
    "e": "She yawns.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Agatha’s relationship with the Electric Grandmother differ from that of her siblings?",
    "a": "Agatha is the first to trust the Electric Grandmother.",
    "b": "Agatha refuses to be friends with the Electric Grandmother.",
    "c": "Agatha receives the special responsibility of maintaining the Electric Grandmother’s circuitry.",
    "d": "Agatha is the Electric Grandmother’s favorite child.",
    "e": "Agatha thinks the Electric Grandmother is frightening.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which item first emerges from the Electrical Grandma’s finger in “I Sing the Body Electric!”?",
    "a": "water",
    "b": "a toothbrush",
    "c": "string",
    "d": "chocolate",
    "e": "a feather duster",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, to prove to Tom that she can really remember things, Grandma gives him a(n)",
    "a": "chalkboard",
    "b": "origami crane",
    "c": "fortune cookie",
    "d": "cassette tape",
    "e": "piece of paper",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which author’s works does Grandma read to Tom in “I Sing the Body Electric!”?",
    "a": "Leo Tolstoy’s",
    "b": "Charles Dickens’s",
    "c": "Edgar Allen Poe’s",
    "d": "Mary Shelley’s",
    "e": "Mark Twain’s",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, the Electrical Grandma’s food reminds the children’s father of the food at a restaurant in",
    "a": "Italy",
    "b": "Russia",
    "c": "Germany",
    "d": "Great Britain",
    "e": "France",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following claims does Grandma NOT make in “I Sing the Body Electric!”?",
    "a": "The morals of machines are shaped by humans.",
    "b": "Machines are equally capable of logic reasoning and thought as humans.",
    "c": "Despite being a robot, Grandma is just as capable of loving and being loved.",
    "d": "Machines are not inherently cold or awful, and are capable of doing great things.",
    "e": "Though she is not perfect, Grandma cannot commit a sin.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following incidents apparently “kills” Grandma in “I Sing the Body Electric!”?",
    "a": "a kitchen fire",
    "b": "an earthquake",
    "c": "the rain",
    "d": "a flood",
    "e": "a car crash",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Agatha claim to hate her late mother in “I Sing the Body Electric!”?",
    "a": "Agatha is miffed by her mother’s neglect of her and her siblings.",
    "b": "Agatha is confused between her distaste for her mother and her grief.",
    "c": "Agatha finds it difficult to accept that her mother was not a good person.",
    "d": "Agatha is filled with resentment because her mother “left” her with no explanation.",
    "e": "Agatha was smothered by her mother, but misses her now that she’s gone.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, Grandma says she can be sent to",
    "a": "a quarry where her parts will be used to build other robots",
    "b": "a room where she can socialize with other robots",
    "c": "a resort where she can peacefully retire from her job as caretaker",
    "d": "a house with more children for her to take care of",
    "e": "a factory where she can be improved and refined",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, the walls of Tom’s childhood bedroom display",
    "a": "planets and stars",
    "b": "dinosaurs",
    "c": "superheroes",
    "d": "robots",
    "e": "wild animals",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which poet wrote the poem for which “I Sing the Body Electric!” is named?",
    "a": "Sylvia Plath",
    "b": "T. S. Eliot",
    "c": "Robert Frost",
    "d": "Walt Whitman",
    "e": "Shel Silverstein",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which United States president did Ray Bradbury receive the National Medal of Arts?",
    "a": "George W. Bush",
    "b": "Bill Clinton",
    "c": "Donald Trump",
    "d": "Barack Obama",
    "e": "Ronald Reagan",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the children’s father in “I Sing the Body Electric!”, what does fantoccini mean?",
    "a": "“hot air balloons”",
    "b": "“robots”",
    "c": "“paper airplanes”",
    "d": "“shadow puppets”",
    "e": "“ghosts”",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which god’s movement does Tom compare the delivery of the Electrical Grandmother, in “I Sing the Body Electric!”?",
    "a": "Athena",
    "b": "Zeus",
    "c": "Poseidon",
    "d": "Hermes",
    "e": "Apollo",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “I Sing the Body Electric!”, how does Agatha feel FIRST toward Grandma?",
    "a": "excited",
    "b": "loving",
    "c": "indifferent",
    "d": "scornful",
    "e": "wary",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what point does Grandma decide to leave the children, in “I Sing the Body Electric!”?",
    "a": "when Timothy has his first child",
    "b": "when Agatha leaves to go to college",
    "c": "when Tom leaves the house for the first time",
    "d": "when the children’s father remarries",
    "e": "when the children have moved on from their mother’s death",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]

